SHANDEEP SRINIVAS

Dubai, United Arab Emirates

c.shandeep@gmail.com \diamond @shandeepsrinivas \diamond shandeep.dev

OBJECTIVE

Senior IAM Technical Consultant with 5.5+ years of experience in SailPoint IIQ, ISC, FAM, ForgeRock AM Suite & Ping Federate. Integrated various critical enterprise application with above products using multiple complex, custom and first in the industry solutions. Have core domain knowledge and strong product knowledge.

Aspire to become an expert in the Identity And Access Management domain.

seeking full-time Identity And Access Management roles.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology - Information Technology, Anna University

2015 - 2019

SKILLS

Product Expertise SailPoint IIQ, ISC & FAM, ForgeRock IDM & AM Suite,

Ping Federate, Oracle OIM & OAM, Keycloak, Swivel Secure SSO, Ansible

Industry Experience Banking and Finance, Retail, Health, Defense,

Investment Authorities, Telecom, Real Estate, Federal Authorities

Programming Languages Java, Python, Groovy, JavaScript, TypeScript, Bean Shell, Shell script, PowerShell

Frameworks Hibernate, Spring, Angular, Bootstrap

EXPERIENCE

IAM Developer 2019 – 2022

Tata Consultancy Services

RNS Technology Services

Chennai, India

- Worked for a largest financial institution in Europe.
- Migrated from IIQ 7.0 to 8.0
- Managed approx 250k Identities & 200+ Application
- Implemented organization wide RBAC and various automations using IIQ
- CyberArk PAM, RACF, OICS & Main Frame system integration with IIQ.

Implementation Engineer - IAM

2022 - 2023

30

Dubai, United Arab Emirates

- Worked for a largest financial institution in UAE & Qatar.
- IIQ Installation, Upgrade and Migration from Other products.
- Non-Employee Life Cycle Management.
- Integrated 200+ Application with RBAC within 1 Year
- BMC Remedy & Helix, ManageEngine ServiceDesk bi-directional ticketing system integration using Custom Integration Configuration
- SailPoint FAM Installation, Configuration & Upgrade
- Developed Custom Connectors and Custom Frameworks for various customer requirements.

RNS Technology Services

- Worked with Telecoms provider, Defense, Retail & Financial institution.
- Led the migration and implementation of Africa's largest Telecoms provider from ISAM/ISIM to SailPoint IIQ & ForgeRock Access Management Suite
- Integrated 100+ IIQ Applications & 100+ SSO integration in AM using SAML2.0, OAuth2.0, OIDC, Social Providers e.t.c
- Full fledged Life Cycle & Password management for Employees & Non-Employees using SailPoint IIQ & Forge-Rock Access Management
- Multiple custom AM node development for various customer requirements and legacy application integration for SSO.

Senior Technical Consultant - IAM

2024 - Present

RNS Technology Services

Dubai, United Arab Emirates

- Implementation of CIAM, MFA, Authorization Policies, Contextual Authentication.
- Deployed and managed 16 ForgeRock AM Suite instances in different countries for load balancing and seamless user experience.
- PasswordLess & Usernameless login implementation using FiFo & WebAuthN.
- ForgeRock AM & SailPoint IIQ Deployment, Configuration, Upgrade, Patching & Maintenance automation using Ansible.
- Managed a team under myself for SailPoint & ForgeRock Projects

PERSONAL PROJECTS & COMMUNITY CONTRIBUTIONS

Announcement - IdenityIQ Plugin. This plugin can be used to display Scrolling Text on top of the Home Page. This one of the most requested feature by many client.

This Plugin is published in SailPoint Developer Community (Here)

Identity Details Tweaks - IdenityIQ Plugin. Allows tweaking Identity Details Page - Attribute, Access, Accounts & Passwords. Allows implementers to disable, hide few features & details that are not possible by OOTB customization

This Plugin is published in SailPoint Developer Community (Here)

Custom Loading Spinner - IdenityIQ Plugin. Allows implementers to replace the OOTB loading spinner to customer logo or any image needed.

This Plugin is published in SailPoint Developer Community (Here)

Lysandra - REST API. A simple REST API built using Node.js and Express.js. Uses JSON files for persistence storage.

This tool can be used for learning Web-Services connector, It can be configure to serve a REST API from simple to Very complex where custom logics are required to handle the data.

This Tool is published in GitHub as open source (Here)

CERTIFICATIONS & ACHIEVEMENTS

- SailPoint Certified IdentityIQ Engineer (Here).
- SailPoint Developer Community Ambassador (Here).
- SailPoint Identity Security Leader(Here).